# Chiedu Humphrey Orjiako 32 Laurelwood Drive, Stoughton, MA 978.501.0008 chorjiako@gmail.com

## **Summary of Qualifications:**

Multi-talented, strategically and operationally focused professional with years of science, lean and operational excellence experience. Adept at stabilizing and improving processes; using strong analytical skills; relationship building and communication skills, and regarded as a trusted advisor, leader and 'team-first' colleague. Proven to meet the demands of any organization across multiple industries, highly motivated and consistently exceeding expectations with concise attention to detail and distinct ability to proactively multitask, prioritize and meet critical deadlines with enthusiasm.

## **Professional Experience:**

# **Liberty Mutual, Boston, MA**

2013 - Present

### LMS/Lean Manager, Corporate Deployments, 2015 – Present

- Partner with business leaders (Managers, Directors, VPs) in the planning and designing of the management system to provide solutions to business process gaps and enable them to understand their role to drive continuous improvement across the organization
- Implemented Lean management system/LMS (Liberty Management System) across various business units under corporate with strong success in their target measures:
  - Ouality achieved increase in quality measures ranging from 1% 10% across all transformations
  - Timeliness met or exceeded timing objectives by an average of 10% across all transformations
  - o Productivity steady increases in productivity measures
  - Overall 87% of the leaders agreed that transformations have supported sustainable business results
- On track to delivering approximately \$300,000/year in cost-savings within the Corporate Procurement group by streamlining the procure to pay (P2P) process, and enhancing operational productivity
- Improved transformation engagement satisfaction by 20% in the corporate department by enhancing the efficiency and effectiveness of the transformation process through the successful execution of complex crossfunctional problem solving efforts
- Created (currently piloting) new methodology -Value Stream Management- this approach has improved leadership effectiveness measures by more than 25% with tested groups both employees and leaders are more strategically and tactically aligned
- Managed the development of several LMS coaches (Lean coaches/change agents) 100% of my eligible direct reports received the LMS professional certification
- Coach certification program lead for corporate guided and advised all LMS coaches under corporate through the certification process Corporate has had one of the highest coach certification success rate in Liberty

#### LMS/Lean Associate Consultant, Continuous Improvement, 2013 - 2015

- Integral part of team that designed and developed the 'Management System Maturity Assessment' process to evaluate LMS/Lean maturity and efficacy and close gaps in the management system to drive business results
- Conducted LMS maturity assessments of various groups across multiple business units including; IT, Corporate, Commercial, and US consumer markets
- Conducted the first international LMS maturity assessment in Liberty Seguros (Brazil); evaluated their maturity
  efficacy, problem solved on their identified gaps, developed action plans and provided consultative guidance to
  achieve business goals
- Collaborated with IT and analytics group to develop an enterprise wide continuous improvement tracker used to capture opportunities and help teams to solve the right problems at the right time
- Managed the methodology governance for the LMS organization during my oversight the team improved the governance process yielding savings of over 500 man-hours; \$100k yearly and 36% boost in productivity
- Core member of a vital transformation study that seeks to evaluate the effectiveness and opportunities across transformations conducted in various business units in order to share best practices, reduce variation and improve on methodology

### Operational Excellence Leader

- Continuous improvement analysis for Fabrazyme site, using lean and six sigma to identify resources required to successfully execute projects
- Led projects to implement ongoing process management mechanisms (process mapping, documentation, metrics, monitoring systems and process control techniques)
- Received 1st place in the 2013 Sanofi "Industrial Innovation Award" for project as the top Lean implementation globally:
  - The project improved the bulk release lead time for the for the site's primary product from 101+ days to approximately 50 days, resulting in approximately a \$40M gain in sales, reduced variability in delivery by 60% and reduced product shortage in the market
- Led a lean project to eliminate inefficiencies of a critical release process of the site's most vital product from upstream to downstream processing, reducing the lead time by > 40% (from 52 days to 30 days) enabled the site to increase inventory levels for downstream processing and contributing to the reduction in product shortage
- Liaison between production floor and management and other support groups within plant (Quality Control, Quality Assurance, engineering, manufacturing, Tech Support)
- Partnered with IT group on the implementation of various visual management software for the different functional groups (QC, QA, Mfg) to aid in tracking performance
- Oversaw the IT implementation which eliminated 75% of the administrative activities for the Quality Assurance group and 4 FTE time savings for Quality Control; helped site surpass delivery metrics
- Successfully developed a safety rewards program for the Facilities and Engineering department to recognize the successful safety improvement efforts by the workers on the floor
- Collaborate with leaders to execute 'Gemba' walk process (Managing for Daily Improvement), utilizing and constantly improving the visual management on shop floor and in office areas

# Pfizer, Inc., Andover, MA Scientist, 2006-2011

2006 - 2011

- Successfully utilized phenotypic and genotypic methods (molecular techniques, PCR) to support commercial drug substance manufacturing
- Oversaw Six Sigma initiatives testing and improving assessments (via Kaizen/5S etc.), producing logistics/cost analysis on systems/processes; accurately obtained key metrics and presented business cases supporting Lean goals
- Featured in Pfizer's continuous improvement annual report for successful lean projects
- Led project conducting comprehensive efficiency analysis of an assay/testing procedure and persuaded management to permit removal from process subsequently saving \$10K per year
- Managed project to evaluate critical media integrity test for lab, identified and eliminated process wastes and inefficiencies resulting in savings of over \$20k annually with man-hours for staff additional benefit was enhanced communication between various groups with visual management boards
- Created standard work, restructuring the microbial identification process, increasing productivity by 32% and created savings of \$25k annually and 0.5 FTE per month, enabling management to better level load tasks and manage the work schedule and maximize resources
- Managed Biological indicator (BI) testing for lab and point of contact for vendor relations working closely with legal on the labor of agreements; created request system to support entire site for validation testing.
- Utilized SharePoint and other Microsoft systems, improving lines of communication between groups, reducing request errors by 10-20% and streamlining process

## QC Investigations Coordinator, 2006

- Lead QC Investigator supporting the Microbiology, Biochemistry, Quality Assurance, and other QC groups
- Documented investigation reports and partnered with impacted departments to complete investigations and determine best practices and corrective actions

## **Technical Skills:**

SharePoint, Metrics, Phenotypic and Genotypic Methods, PCR, Pharmaceutical, GMP, Data Review, 5S, Documentation, OQ, PQ, Six Sigma, Kaizen, BIZ IQ's, Quality Control, Out of Tolerance Reports, Data Analysis, Deviation and Data Trending, Root Cause Analysis, Microsoft Office (Visio, Project, Word, PowerPoint, Excel), Labware LIMS, GLP, PMBOK, MES, Delta V, Trackwise, Mind Map, Value stream Mapping, Standard work, Change management, 5 Why's, Gantt charts, Bottleneck Analysis, Failure Modes and Effects Analysis (FMEA), JIT/Inventory Reduction, Kaizen Events, Level Loading, One Piece Flow, Pareto Chart, Error-proofing, Spaghetti Diagram, Visual Management, Time Study, Critical Path Method, PDCA, Coaching, project management.

## **Certifications:**

Six Sigma trained – Yellow Belt Lean Silver certification- pending

## **Professional Development:**

Certificate – Applied Project Management, Boston University Knowledge sharing seminars/workshops, Europe (UK, Ireland), MDI (managing for daily improvement)

## **Education:**

University of Massachusetts, Dartmouth/Lowell, MA

Masters of Business Administration Bachelor of Science in Biology-Biotechnology